When you committed this murder.
How did you feel afterwards?
Have you felt any debt and regret after that?
Have you cried after that?
Have you cried in your life at all?
This is the series about crime.
A personality taken to its extreme.
When measuring and wanting to diagnose psychopathy
So you usually divide it into three, sometimes four, dimensions.
The first dimension is the interpersonal.
The interpersonal.
Lying, manipulating, is grandiose and bloated.
To the narcissistic direction in relation to other people.
The second is the emotional dimension.
Lack of empathy.
Superficial emotional life.
Don't get nuanced sad.
If you get angry you get very angry.
Although it may not be so.
What you try to do is interview the person and people in the surroundings.
And asks more concrete questions:
Has something serious happened in your life?
How did you feel?
When you committed this murder?
How did you feel afterwards?
Have you felt any debt and regret after that?
Have you cried after that?
Have you cried in your life at all?
What are you crying over?
Depending on purpose and where you are somewhere, you may need to use different types of instruments.
Yes, is your partner psychopath really?
How likely is that?
If we only look at the statistics, we believe that 1-2 percent are psychopaths.
Probably the person can show traits that are psychopathic.
Maybe fails in empathy, but not grandiose, lying or impulsive.
However, if the person is impulsive, needs change, deficiencies in empathy and superficial emotional life.
And is lying and manipulative.
Now we are starting to see a psychopathic syndrome.
And we should probably suspect psychopathy if you see those personality traits.
And it has major negative consequences.
You violate rules, are violent and threatening.
Commits some form of financial crime or whatever it may be.
And don't forget to subscribe, of course.
I have been researching crimes for more than 20 years now.
And I educate the criminologists of the future here at Örebro University.
I also train professional police officers and officials
Out in the municipalities that have the task of creating security and security in your particular municipality.
I think it's important for all citizens to meet a more nuanced picture
Otherwise, we may be unnecessary to suffer from crime.
We may lose confidence in the legal system.
Due to the distorted reporting of crime.
Have you thought that you have a role in preventing crime?
You can have a role.
I can have a role.